孩子们 圣诞节是一家团聚的日子
Kids, as you know, Christmas is a time you spend with your family.
在2006年的圣诞 我有三个选择
So in December of 2006, I had three options.
和我妈妈还有 他的新男友克林特过圣诞
Spend it with my mom and her new boyfriend Clint,
也可以去找我爸爸 还有他的小甜心
spend it with my dad and his new girlfriend micro-brewing,
或者乖乖待在斯塔藤岛
or head down to Staten Island to spend it
和我那异常虔诚的堂姐斯坦西 还有她的家人一起度过
with my super religious cousin Stacy and her family.
但是以上三个选择我都放弃了
So I opted for none of the above
决定在曼哈顿过2006年的圣诞
and decided to spend Christmas 2006 in Manhattan...
和我的特殊家人一起过圣诞
celebrating with my other family.
我最后一场考试在 今天下午五点
Okay, I have one last paper due at 5:00 p.m. today,
在考试之前 我都要在图书馆里复习
so until then, I will be at the law library at school,
没有任何事情可以改变我的计划
but I'm not to be disturbed for any reason.
老兄 睁开你的眼睛 你会摔到的
Dude, open your eyes. You're going to hurt yourself.
不  不  对于我来说 平安夜所营造的冬日幻境
No, no. Christmas Eve winter wonderland is my reward
就是对我胜利完成考试的奖励
for finishing my paper.
我闻到了浓浓的 肉桂曲奇的香味了  亲爱的
Baby, do I smell your Sinfully Cinnamon Cookies?
没错
Yes.
见鬼  我其他感官 的敏感度太高了
Damn me and my heightened other senses.
一定很敏感
Must be strong.
我出门了 我5点回来
Okay, I'll be back here at 5:00.
给我留20块曲奇 记住不要把碗洗了
Save me at least 20 cookies and do not clean the bowl.
这是个驯鹿!
Was that a reindeer?
不要告诉我 (我要亲眼看)
I don't want to know!
我们原来的那个电话答录机
Hey, look. Our old answering machine.
是啊 你从你走后 我们...我们就把它拆了
Oh, yeah. After you left, we, uh, we unplugged it
这个容易让马修睹物思人 因为你以前经常用它
because it reminded Marshall of how you used to, you know, leave messages.
但是你们已经破镜重圆了
But hey, you guys are back together.
我建议我们把它装回去
I say we're plugging it back in.
算是你对回来的庆祝
It's good to have you back.
谢谢
Thanks.
里面还有些信息呢
Oh, hey, look, there's still some messages on here.
泰德 这是你老爹
Hey Ted, it's Dad calling to check in.
这个周末我要和克林特去钓鱼
I'm going fishing this weekend with my friend Clint,
如果你留言给我的话 我下周回复你
so if I don't hear from you beforehand, I'll talk to you next week.
是的 克林特 （泰德母亲的新男友)
Yes, same Clint.
马修 还在躺在沙发上 为莉莉的离开垂头丧气啊
Hey, Marshall. Are you lying on the couch right now moping about Lily?
你在吗?不是这样的吗?
You are, aren't you?
不要再这样了 她不值得你这样...
Well, stop it. She's not worth it.
你应该忘记那个烂人
You gotta get over that Grinch.
事实上我没有说 烂人
But I didn't say "Grinch."
我说了个更糟的词
I said a bad word.
非常非常糟的...
A very, very bad word.
虚假
Oh, fudge.
事实上我不是想说这是假的 (而是上帝啊)
But I didn't say fudge.
本字幕由YYeTs美剧字幕组原创翻译制作
仅供学习交流之用 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
欢迎访问YYeTs美剧论坛进行交流 www.YYETS.com
老爸老妈的浪漫史
第二季 第十一集
翻译：    唐伯虎点雷管        校对：     贝壳刘
后期：     oliver0951      字幕监制：  叶煦   雨亦奇
我....什么?
I'm... a what?
我...是巴尼 这个是巴尼说的
I-- That was Barney, that was Barney.
- 泰德 不要说谎 - 是马修
- That was you, Ted. - That was Marshall.
马修给自己留言?
Marshall left a message for Marshall?
这个也许是我 但是这个是很早以前的了
You know, it may have been me, but it was so long ago.
这个机器总把声音录的失真
Man, that machine, it really garbles your voice.
所以听上去像是我说的 实际...
You know, it almost made it sound like I said...
你为什么叫我那个?
Why would you call me that?
这个是个很难回答的问题
It was a fair question.
马修跟莉莉分手以后 他的情绪实在不好
Marshall's breakup with Lily had sent him into a deep depression
没有什么可以帮他 走出失恋的痛苦
and nothing could get him out of it.
直到那天...
Until one day...
她太完美了
She was perfect.
我失去了一个我梦寐以求的女人
I lost the perfect woman.
她给我机会时我该追上去的
I should have knocked her up when I had the chance.
够了
Okay. That's it.
如果你还在继续神话她 那么你将永远都忘不了她
You're never going to get over her until you stop putting her on a pedestal.
告诉我一件莉莉做错的事情 要不就没有冰淇淋吃了
So no more ice cream until you tell me one thing that's wrong with Lily.
她只做过一件错事 (哇～只有一件错事的人多完美啊)
There's only one of her?
好吧
Okay.
她不跟你结婚了
She called off your wedding
弃你而去之后 你在旧金山沦为个油漆匠
and dumped you to be a painter in San Francisco.
你管她叫什么?
What do you call that?
自我独立?
Fiercely independent?
勇气?
Brave?
我认为有点自私
I guess it was a little selfish.
对了!
There you go.
在短时间内 星星之火  开始燎原了
And in almost no time, that spark turned into a roaring fire.
对 你是对的 莉莉会嘲笑身边所有事情
Yeah. No, you're right. Lily would laugh at anything.
她总是用一个很糟的理由 来表示她放弃了
She'd give it up for a bad pun.
我告诉你她的快乐神经有问题
I'm telling you, she's a laugh slut.
记得那次她大笑的事情吗?
Remember that time we heard her laughing
我们认为她在看 '老板度假去'
and we thought she was watching Weekend At Bernie's,
结果她在看 '老板度假去2'
but it turned out she was watching Weekend At Bernie's 2?
她很有艺术细胞?
And her art?
我是莉莉 我是个艺术家
"I'm Lily, I'm an artist."
她甚至都没有得过奖
She doesn't even own a beret.
如果现实如她所说 她是个艺术家
Yeah, and if she's such a great "artist,"
那她还玩pictionary? (pictionary 多人游戏 一人画图一人猜)
why does she suck at Pictionary?
是谁把忍者之星画成了大卫之星? 是她吧?
Who draws a ninja star like a Star of David? Right, right?
是啊!
Yeah!
- 再来庆祝下 - 好的
- Another round! - Yeah!
我是他哥们我当然要帮他啦
I was trying to help him. I'm his best friend.
这就是哥们改作的事情
That's the best friend's job.
是哥们就可以叫我那个?
The best friend's job is to call me that word?
是的
Yeah.
天啊 泰德
Oh, Ted.
泰德你还没有长大啊
Oh, Teddy boy.
就一个单词的事情 有那么严重吗?
Why is this such a big deal? It's just a word.
每天我们都说无数的词
We use lots of words, every day.
它和别的单词应该没有什么区别
It shouldn't be any different than any other word.
那你为什么现在不说?
Then why don't you say it now?
烂人
Grinch.
你在算计我?
You timed that didn't you?
没错
Perfectly.
至少你要道歉啊
Well, at least you apologized.
你道歉了吗?
You apologized, didn't you?
当然
Oh, yeah.
我当时先说  对不起
"I'm sorry" were the first words out of my mouth.
对不起 但是这不是道歉
I'm sorry, but I am not apologizing.
我只是想帮他走出失恋
I was just trying to put the guy back together.
你把他的心撕碎了
You smashed him to pieces.
你就不能因为 一条留言跟我道个歉?
Are you seriously not going to apologize for leaving that message?
-不! - 为什么不?
- No! - Why not?
因为你今年夏天 的确是个烂人
Because, Lily, this summer, you were kind of a Grinch.
- Oooh. - Oooh.
你会后悔的 泰德・莫斯比
Oh, you'll be sorry, Ted Mosby.
泰德・维维安・莫斯比
Ted Vivian Mosby!
我的全名可不是那样
That's not my middle name.
你用那种口气更你妈说话?
好像你从来没有错过那个词一样
Like you've never said that word.
我又没有用那种口气 更你妈说过话
I don't kiss your mother with my mouth.
但是
Yet.
你病了?
Are you sick?
你是不是认为我缺乏性生活?
Is it sick to find maturity and experience sexy?
我是问  你是不是感冒了?
No, I meant do you have a cold?
我很好
I'm fine.
就是我的鼻子里有太多的东西了
I'm fine. My nose is just overflowing with awesome
我需要弄些出来
and I had to get some of it out.
如果你觉得有欠于我
Now, if you'll excuse me, the holidays are a time
假期真是让人孤独  无聊的时候
when people are lonely and desperate.
这是一年里最美好的时候
It's the most wonderful time of the year.
我该去道歉吧 今天是平安夜
I should go apologize. It's Christmas Eve.
一个充满了砸门还有咒骂的平安夜?
Yeah. I mean, slamming doors and screaming curses?
如果我想要那些的话 我可以回家过
If I wanted that, I would have gone home for the holidays.
我没有看见槲寄生 但是...
I don't see any mistletoe, but...
神啊
Oh! Oh, God!
"保佑你" 我本可以做的更好...
Uh... "Bless you" would have been nice.
- 你病了 - 没有
- You're sick. - I'm not sick.
- 你病了 - 你知道什么?我病了
- You're sick. - You know what? I am sick.
你说我病了我就病了!怎么可能?
Sick of you telling me I'm sick. What up?
爬了三层楼一滴也没有洒出来
Ahh... Three flights of stairs, not a drop spilled.
老兄
Hey, buddy.
你确定这个管用?
You sure this is gonna work?
是的 这是我们的方式
Yeah, this is our thing.
大学时  每当我想向她道歉 我就买杯啤酒给她
In college, whenever I wanted to make up with her, I'd buy her a beer.
-有意思吧? - 是的
- Cute, right? - Totally.
加上个免费的杯子
Plus free mug.
起来吧
Okay, come on.
通常这招都有用
Usually that would've done the trick,
但这次的问题是 一杯啤酒不足以解决的
but it turned out this was a problem not even alcohol could solve.
事实上 啤酒确实有点用
Actually the beer helped a little.
她拿走了圣诞装饰
She took the decorations.
她拿走了圣诞装饰!
She took the decorations!
真是个烂人
What a Grinch!
这次我确实说了烂人这个词
That time I did say "Grinch."
好吧
All right.
我想我不得不给她打电话了
I guess I have to call her, right?
莉莉
Lily's cell phone.
她不是想听解释吗?
She'll listen to reason-- right?
你好 比利
Oh, hey, Billy.
事实上这很有趣 语音拨号拨到你那了
Actually, funny thing-- the voice dial got you.
我本打算打给...
I was trying to call...
天啊  很遗憾
Oh, I'm sorry to hear that.
假期对于每一个都是有点粗糙
Yeah, the holidays are a rough time for everyone, Billy.
晚餐在下周三举行
Okay, yeah, dinner next Wednesday.
好
Okay.
该死的语音拨号
Damn voice dial.
巴尼!你在那做什么?
Barney! What the hell are you doing?
进来 外面那么冷 你疯了吗?
Get in here, it's freezing outside. Are you insane?
要怪就怪莉莉的规矩 公寓里禁止吸烟
Hey, blame Lily and her oppressive "no cigars in the apartment rule."
上帝啊 马修 像娶了个塔利班份子一样
God, it's like Marshall's marrying the Taliban.
我很好
High five.
不
Eww. No.
你该回家躺在床上
You have to go home and get to bed.
罗宾 你是从未开化的北方来的
Oh, Robin, my simple friend from the untamed north,
让我来告诉你一些 关于我认为的意识决定物质
let me tell you about a little thing I like to call mind over body.
你也看见了 当我发现我病了
You see, whenever I start feeling sick,
我会用恐惧来吓退病魔
I just stop being sick and be awesome instead.
真的
True story.
在两分钟内
Yeah, in two minutes,
我会喝半打红牛之后跳上出租车
I'm going to pound a sixer of Red Bull, hop in a cab,
玩两小时的激光搏击
play a couple of hours of laser tag,
也可能 是把皮肤弄成阳光色
maybe get a spray-on tan.
这将要...
It's gonna be legen...
等待...
Wait for it...
莉莉!
Lily!
圣诞快乐  屁股脸!
Merry Christmas, assface.
莉莉!圣诞装饰在哪?
Um, Lily? Where are the Christmas decorations?
我公寓里
At my apartment.
你有想把他们送回到这里 来跟我们一起过圣诞的想法吗?求你了
You want to bring them back so we can celebrate Christmas together-- please?
泰德 你知道吗?
Ted, do you know what I would do
如果在幼儿园里 有人用那个词我会怎么做?
if one of my kindergartners used that kind of language?
我会打电话给他的家长
I would be on the phone with their parents.
是啊 但是我可不是小孩
Yeah, I'm not a kindergartner.
事实上你知道那个词的意思
Exactly. You know what that word means.
你也知道用那个来形容别人 会对别人造成伤害...
You know that calling people names is mean and hurtful...
屁股脸
assface.
如果你不那些东西还回来 我们...
Lily, if you don't bring that stuff back right now, we...
她挂了
She hung up.
她现在很激动 她会冷静下来的
She's just mad. She'll cool down.
莉莉...
Lily...
不要忘了把那些曲奇从烤箱里取出
Don't forget to take the cookies out of the oven...
屁股脸!
assface!
见鬼!
Damn it!
我现在应该在克利夫兰 和我爸爸喝着薄荷啤酒
I could be in Cleveland right now making peppermint lager with my dad.
你去哪?
Where are you going?
马修他三小时后回来
Marshall gets home in three hours.
他会发现没有莉莉 就没有冬日幻境
He's gonna show up-- no Lily, no winter wonderland.
我得去找莉莉
I gotta get up to the Bronx.
...工作.
...dary.
兄弟考试怎么样?
Hey, dude, how's the paper going?
什么考试?冬日幻境怎么样?很漂亮?
Screw the paper, how's the winter wonderland? Is it magical?
是啊 有点魔幻的感觉
Oh... so magical.
当你进门的一瞬间 是什么感觉?
When you walk through the door, does it feel like
有没有震惊的感觉?
you've been slapped in the face by Christmas?
确实很震惊 我有事要做  先挂电话了
Sure does. Look, I gotta go.
不要这样 兄弟 描述一下屋子有多漂亮
Come on, man, describe it! Tell me about the decorations.
鲁道夫在那?他在不在?
Is Rudolph there? He is, isn't he?
鲁道夫 你好啊!
Hi, Rudolph!
是  但是你要知道...
Ah, yeah, but, you know...
圣诞精神不单单是装饰?
decorations, is that really what Christmas is about?
该死 是啊! 那还有什么?
Hell, yeah! What else would it be about?
庆祝耶稣的生日
Uh, try the birth of Christ.
你知道 圣诞 是耶稣的生日
You know, Christmas-- Christ Mas,
意味着 更多的爱 给那些需要的人
which means "More Christ" to our Spanish friends.
好吧 好吧 我所知道的是当我走进门
Yeah, well, all I know is walking in that door
看见冬日的幻境 莉莉 还有你们这些朋友
and seeing the winter wonderland and seeing Lily and all you guys,
仅仅... 我等不及了
just... I can't wait.
是的  我真的要挂了
Right. I gotta go.
恩 好
Right. Okay.
等等 泰德 还有件事
Oh, wait. Ted, Ted, Ted, Ted. One more thing.
曲奇怎么样? 好吃吗?
How about the cookies? Are they delicious?
说实话  不像是是家里做的
You know, honestly, they taste a little store-bought.
我有另一个电话来了
Oh! I got another call.
告诉莉莉我爱他
Well, tell Lily I love her.
恩
Right.
- 你好? - 泰德・伊夫林・莫斯比
- Hello? - Ted Evelyn Mosby!
妈妈 圣诞快乐
Oh. Uh, hey, Mom. Merry Christmas.
我刚才接到了莉莉的电话
I just got the most disturbing call from Lily.
你怎么能用那么粗俗的词!
How could you use such a horrible word?
俄地神啊 她打电话给你了?
Oh, God, she called you?
这就是你对我们离婚 作出的回应?
Are you acting out because of the divorce?
难道都是因为克林特?
Is-is this all about Clint?
不是的 妈妈 你为什么会认为是因为克林特?
No, Mom, why would it be about Clint?
兄弟 我是克林特 你做的怎么样?
Hey, buddy, it's Clint. How you doing, champ?
克林特 听好 我没有时间...
Hey, Clint. Listen, um, I don't really have time to...
不是  不是  泰德
Hey, hey, no, no, no. Ted, Ted.
你还不了解情况
You don't know this yet,
但是你我将会成为好友
but you and I are going to be great friends.
现在美国本地人有一种仪式...
Now, the Native Americans have this ritual...
这是巴尼的惨淡时光
This is a low moment for the Barnacle.
我现在应该是 结束激光搏击的时候了
I should be off playing laser tag right now,
但是  事实上
but instead...
不要盯着我  现在我很惨
Don't look at me. I'm hideous.
你看上去是个正常人
You just look like a regular guy.
事实上
Exactly.
我是泰德 我穿着 有莱卡的T恤  羊毛裤
I'm a Ted. I'm wearing elastic-waist fleece pants.
这样不是更舒服吗?
And isn't it more comfy?
是的
Y es.
来  吃点东西吧
Come on, you need eat something.
太虚弱... 拿不动... 碗
Too weak... to hold... bowl.
好吧 我来喂你
Fine, I'll feed you.
烫到嘴了
Ouchie in my mouth!
我不想吃 我想要冰淇淋
I don't want it. I want ice cream.
不行 你晚饭不能 只吃冰淇淋 你病了
No, you're not having ice cream for dinner just 'cause you're sick.
- 但是烫到我舌头了 - 不
- But my throat hurts. - No.
我恨你!
I hate you!
不要离开我
Don't leave me.
谁?
Who is it?
送比萨的
Pizza delivery.
Whoa.
你骗我
Hey, you tricked me.
你真认为我是送比萨的啊?
You really thought I was the pizza delivery guy?
不  我知道是你
No, I knew it was you.
我只是认为 你至少该带个比萨来
I just thought you'd at least bring a pizza.
好吧好吧
Yeah, well,
我本来带了杯啤酒的 但我给了个无家可归的人
I brought a beer, but I gave it to a homeless guy.
好吧 他抢走的
All right, he took it from me.
现在 你愿意回去了吗?
Now, will you please come home?
我是不会和你过圣诞的
No, I'm not spending Christmas with you.
好吧 叫你那个 是我错了...
Okay, I'm sorry for calling you a...
那个词
that word,
整个夏天
over the summer,
还有今天又说了
and for saying it again today.
坐地铁来着的路上 我想了很多
And for thinking it a lot on the subway ride over.
我没权利骂你 这个是很伤人的 同时也是我不成熟的表现 我错了
I had no right to say that. It was hurtful and immature and I'm sorry.
等下...
Oh, shut up.
你以为我不知道现在你口是心非? 泰德・莫斯比
You think I don't know your fake apologies by now, Ted Mosby? Huh?
你现在依然在生我的气
You're clearly still mad at me.
- 我没有生你的气 - 有 你是在生气
- I'm not mad at you. - Yes, you are.
莉莉 我没有生气 现在 我能不能...
I am not mad at you, Lily. Now, can we please just...
我向马修道歉了 他原谅我了
I've apologized to Marshall and he's forgiven me
我们就这样过去了 为什么你不能?
and we've moved passed it. Why can't you?
因为你从来没有向我道歉
Because you never apologized to me.
马修不是惟一 一个因为你受伤的人
Marshall's not the only one you walked out on.
你走了三个月 一个电话也没有
You leave for three months, you don't even call.
莉莉 我们是朋友啊!
Come on, Lily, we're supposed to be friends!
是啊  我们是朋友 但你骂我是个烂人
Yeah, some friend, you called me a Grinch.
- 你以前就是个烂人! - 你怎么能...
- You were a Grinch! - How can you...
烂人  烂人  烂人 超级烂人  无敌烂人
Grinchy, Grinch, Grinch, Grinch, Grinch, Grinch, Grinch.
高兴了?
Happy?
现在你惹恼了 楼上的那个大家伙
Now, you've pissed off the big guy upstairs.
是啊  我相信 上帝才信  如果...
Yeah, I'm sure God cares if I...
你再说那个词一次 我就断了你的水!
You use that language again and I'll turn off your water!
我房东住在我楼上
That's my super. He lives above me.
很好 谢谢你的大嘴
Great. Thanks to your filthy mouth,
现在我要一个人 在黑暗中度过圣诞
now I'm going to have Christmas alone in the dark.
我不是想破坏你的圣诞
Fine. I don't want to ruin Christmas.
你可以去我们那而且 我不会在那碍你的眼睛
You can have the apartment. Don't worry about seeing me there
我去斯塔藤岛 和我的堂姐过圣诞
I'll be in Staten Island with my cousin Stacy.
这....
Just....
Ow.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
平安夜你和你亲戚过?
You're spending Christmas Eve with your family?
亲爱的 对我来说真遗憾
Baby, that sucks. I'm so sorry.
他们人很好 他们只是... 他们只是有那么一点点怪异
Uh, they're fine. They're just... they're a little weird.
他们不相信礼物还有圣诞树
You know they don't believe in gifts or Christmas trees.
他们还会想
And they think Santa's how Satan spells his name
当圣诞老人想骗 我们的时候用哪个名字
when he wants to trick us.
你希望我跟你一起去吗?
Well, do you want me to go with you?
这是真的?
Was that a sincere offer?
先告诉答案
First tell me your answer.
待在那  自己多保重
Stay there. Save yourself.
明天我们可以在一起
We'll spend all day together tomorrow.
好吧
Okay.
巴尼好些了吗?
Oh, how's Barney feeling?
你指的是那个在生病 还牢骚满腹的那个?
You mean the whiney bottomless pit of neediness?
他骚扰我所以我在他的松果菊茶里 加了点可待因
He was bugging me, so I spiked his echinacea tea with codeine.
你会成为一个伟大的母亲
You're gonna be a great mom.
天啊  奇妙的圣诞到来了
Holy crap, the magical Christmas season is upon us.
感谢上帝  我们没有交物管费
And thank God we don't pay for utilities.
圣诞快乐!
Merry Christmas!
盒子里有什么?
What's in the box?
最好的礼物送给最完美的你
Only the best present for the best girl ever.
找到它花了我一整天的时间
It took me all day to track it down.
我以为你在考试
I thought you were writing a paper.
不是 我没有考 我将参加补考
Ah, naw, I blew that off. I'll get an extension.
学校里的事情不是最重要的
School's not important.
那些在房顶上 噼啪作响的是什么?
What is that pitter patter on the roof?
听上去像圣诞节的恐怖故事
Could it be the sound of an awesome Christmas story
是关于烟囱出来的怪物的?
about to come down the chimney?
为什么 是的 有这么个故事
Why, yes, it is.
圣诞的两天前...
'Twas the day before Christmas...
他说五天前就会到的
It was supposed to arrive, like, five days ago,
但是它变更了时间 不见了
but then it got lost and rerouted.
我问了两家分理处 最后他们说包裹在这里
I checked two other branches, finally they told me it was here.
我所要知道的就是运单号码
Yeah, all I needed to know was the tracking number.
上面说你的包裹刚刚 向波基普西的分理处寄出的
Looks like it's headed out to our regional branch in Poughkeepsie.
什么?
What?
不  不  我今天就要那个包裹
No, no, no, no, I need that package today.
五分钟前车已经开了
Listen, the truck already left five minutes ago,
除非你愿意去追...
so unless you want to run after it...
停车!停车!
Stop! Stop!
停车!请停车!
Stop, please, stop.
把车停下
Stop. Stop the truck.
你车上有我想要的包裹 我可以看看后面吗?
I need a package on your truck. Can I please take a look in back?
可以啊  但是我可不能停车
Sure. But I gotta keep driving my route.
我已经慢了
I'm running behind.
还好吗?
My bad.
很好
I'm okay.
太感谢你的帮助了 帮我完成我美好的圣诞
Hey, man, thanks for helping me make my fiance's Christmas.
没关系
No problem.
可惜我在今天结束的时候不能 把这些东西全部送到客户手里了
Too bad I can't deliver all these packages by the end of the day.
你的意思是有些人 不能准时拿到圣诞礼物?
Wait, so some people aren't going to get their gifts in time for Christmas?
很可惜  是的
Sadly, no.
# They call me back door Santa #
# I make my runs # # about the break of day #
# Oh, ho, ho #
# I make all # # the little girls happy... #
我们送完了车上的每一个包裹
We delivered every single package on that truck.
但是我还有一个包裹需要送
But I still have one package left to give.
是的 我做到了
Yeah, I did.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
- 亲爱的 打开它 - 好的
- Open it, Baby. - Okay.
上帝啊
Oh, my God.
快速烤面包机
An Easy Bake Oven!
但我还是个小孩的时候 我就想要一个
I've wanted one of these ever since I was a little girl.
就是这个东西
In this exact model.
我从来都没有跟你说过 你怎么知道的?
I never told you that. How did you know?
这是我们和好之后的第一个圣诞
It's our first Christmas since we got back together.
我向送她点与众不同的
I want to get her something really special.
所以我想送他个自动点唱机
So I'm getting her a jukebox.
确实是个好礼物
Wow, that's a great gift.
不是啦 它只有这么大 还是用来装口香糖的
Not really. It's this big and it dispenses gum.
兄弟 我知道你送她么最好了
Oh, man, I know something you could get her
是她最想要的
that would blow her mind.
准备好了?
Ready?
八年前
Eight years ago...
当我还是个孩子的时候 快速烤面包机就是我最想要的
When I was a kid, all I wanted was an Easy Bake Oven.
我一再的要求我 那位女权主义的母亲
I begged and I begged,
最后我得到的是 傻啦吧唧的乐高积木
but all I got was a stupid Lego set because my feminist mom
她不想让我成为一个传统的女性
didn't want me conforming to traditional gender roles.
快速烤面包机 这就是我叫做的前卫
Easy Bake Oven-- that's what I'm going to call my van.
哥们... 音乐会怎么样?
Dude... how was the concert?
我在外面找不到入口
I couldn't find the outside.
我简直不能相信泰德 居然还记得那么多年前的事情
I can't believe Ted remembered after all these years.
是啊  在除去了 所有乱七八糟的东西之后
Yeah, and after all that weed.
他去哪了?
Where is he anyway?
斯塔藤岛
Staten Island.
为什么?
Why?
我没有告诉你们的妈妈 但是我给你们带礼物了
Okay, don't tell your mom, but I got you guys some presents.
就像上帝的爱那种礼物?
Like the gift of God's love?
不是 小朋友 是真正的礼物
No, dude, real presents.
泰德叔叔给我们带礼物了!
Uncle Ted got us presents!
泰德 这很好 我们可以 把礼物给慈善团体
That's okay, Ted, we'll just give them to charity.
Yay!
不是你  查瑞迪
Uh, not you, Charity.
我指的是那些不幸的人
I meant the less fortunate.
泰德 今晚你想说些什么?
Ted, how would you like to say grace tonight?
你知道吗?你为什么不自己说呢?
Uh, you know what, why don't you say it.
我真不知道该说什么
I really wouldn't know what to say.
你为什么不背诵圣经里 你最喜欢的那一篇?
Why don't you recite your favorite passage of scripture.
查瑞迪 好主意
That's a great idea, Charity.
但是 事实上 我不知道
But, really, I don't know.
我的意思是你怎么确定你最欢的?
I mean how do you choose your favorite passage?
这个是圣经里面 有太多太多的经典了...
It's the Bible; there's so many... great ones...
黑色通缉令那节很不错
That one from Pulp Fiction's pretty cool.
我去开门 查瑞迪 你来吧
Ooh, I'll get it. Charity, I'm tapping you in.
伟大的主 今天我们在这感谢你
Dear, Father, thank you for this day,
感谢你让一家人团聚
and thank you for bringing this family together.
阿门
Amen.
泰德 谁来了?
Who is it, Ted?
是... 是唱诗的
Uh, it's... it's just, um, carolers.
# Silent night #
# Holy night... #
I came here to apologize.
请接受我得道歉 对不起  泰德
I'm so sorry, Ted.
我接受你的道歉 把啤酒给我
I accept. Give me the beer.
看见你们真的很高兴
Oh, oh, it is so good to see you guys.
你回家吗?
Are you coming home?
当然
Totally.
但是首先 莉莉 我欠你个对不起
But first, Lily, I owe you an apology.
看在上帝的面份上 你像我一样厌恶道歉?
Oh, for the love of God, are you as sick of apologies as I am?
是的!
Yes!
我们能不能忘记那些 直接原谅对方?
Can we just skip the apology and go straight to the forgiving?
是的
Yes.
我保证 我永远不会 再用那个词来骂你
And I promise, I will never ever call you a... you know, again.
好吧
That's okay.
我确实是烂人
I was kind of a Grinch.
什么是烂人?
What's a Grinch?
没什么  是些 你不应该说的的词
Nothing. It's something you shouldn't say.
妈妈  什么是烂人?
Mom, what's a Grinch?
烂人 烂人 烂人...
Grinch, Grinch, Grinch...
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas, everybody.
跑 快跑
Run, run.
马修  圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas, Marshall.